Finding Aid for Linda DeLeon papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Linda DeLeon papers, 1981-2013
DeLeon, Linda
1 linear foot
2013100 Aa 2
Papers of Linda DeLeon, President of the Christians for Decency (CFD) Anti-Pornography Information Center in Wayne County, Michigan. Collection includes CFD and other organizations' correspondence, mailings, petitions, and printed material.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Linda DeLeon (Donor No. 10965 ) in July-August 2013
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Linda DeLeon --previous married name is Cooper--is member of the Christians for Decency (CFD) and President of CFD Anti-Pornography Information Center in Wayne County, Michigan. Anti-pornography and anti-abortion activism are two central among DeLeon's causes. Since the 1980s she has organized petitions and led movements against presence of adult entertainment businesses in the city of Inkster and elsewhere in Wayne County, Michigan.
Collection includes material of DeLeon's organization, Christians Decency, as well as other organizations that share CFD's causes: American Family Association, American Decency Association, Focus on the Family, among others. Also included a small number of subject files and various petitions.
CDF material dated before 1987 show organization's official address in Inkster, Mich.; on materials dated after 1988 CDF is indicated having a Garden City, Mich. address. CDF files, dated between 1985 and 2011, include correspondence, much of it is DeLeon's exchanges with Inkster and Detroit city officials, offices of the State and the City of Inkster Attorneys, U.S. senators, managers and owners of local bookstores and adult movie theaters, as well as officers of national corporations, church pastors and ministers, and leaders of other Michigan conservative organizations. DeLeon's correspondence is mostly on the subject of pornography in public advertising, exposure of children to pornographic images, and sexual violence. Also included are CDF flyers and information mailed to its members.
Material of other organizations, Michigan, national and located in other states, include articles, newsletters, updates, calls to petition, and other material mailed to members. The American Family Association (AFA) Michigan includes runs of its several publications, most notably AFA of Michigan Frontline (1998-2013), among other material.
Subjects:
DeLeon, Linda.; African Americans--Michigan--Inkster.; American Family Association.; Christians for Decency.; Inskter (Mich.); Pornography--Law and legislation--Michigan.; Pro-life movement--Michigan.
- Linda DeLeon papers
  - Abortion, 1984-2011 and undated (with gaps) (Box 1)
  - American Decency Association, Michigan
    - 1999-2013 with gaps (Box 1)
    - American Decency Update, 1999-2003 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - American Family Association of Michigan
    - 1986-1999 (Box 1)
    - American Family Update, 1992 and 1999 (Box 1)
    - AFA of Michigan Reporter, 1994-1997, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - AFA of Michigan Frontline, 1998-2013, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - American Family Association, national and state organizations, 1986-1991 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - Americans for Responsible Television, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Focus on the Family, 1994-2004 and undated (Box 1)
  - Christians for Decency
    - 1985-1989 (Box 1)
    - 1991-2011 with gaps (Box 1)
  - Missing and exploited children, 1986-1996 (Box 1)
  - National Federation for Decency Greater Detroit Chapter, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings and articles, late 1980s-2009 (Box 1)
  - Other organizations
    - Michigan, 1988-2012 (with gaps) (Box 1)
    - National and other states, 1981-2013 (Box 1)
  - Petitions, 1985-1987 and undated (Box 1)